<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[SpaceandShells]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[SpaceandShells]]></description>
        <link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 15:37:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="undefinedrss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>GrindTV SURF NATURE TRAVEL SECTIONS       Southern California red crab invasion intensifies June 19, 2015 by Pete Thomas 10.1K SHARES   Red crabs swarming 1 mile off San Clemente. Photo: ©Geoff Glenn  The invasion of pelagic red crabs along the Southern California coast has intensified during the past week, and judging by photos circulating on the Web, there seems to be no end in sight.  The brightly colored crustaceans, which typically exist in deep water and much farther south, have flooded coastal waters in San Diego and Orange County, and washed onto beaches and into harbors, creating an enormous mess while wreaking minor havoc in the surf zone.   Donna Kalez stoops amid thousands of red crabs at Salt Creek. Photo: Dana Wharf Sportfishing  “They were pinching me out there,” Ethan Mudge, an amateur surfer told the Orange County Register, in reference to a contest last Sunday at Salt Creek in Orange County. “They were hard to paddle through.”  The crabs’ influx, which began about a month ago, is linked either to a strengthening El Niño, a warm-water phenomenon originating in the equatorial eastern Pacific, or another warm-water event referred to by scientists as the “warm blob.”   Red crab hides in the kelp. Photo: ©Geoff Glenn   A lone red crab swims near a kelp bed. Photo: ©Geoff Glenn  Not since the powerful El Niño of 1997-98 has there been a red crab invasion in Southern California that came close to resembling this one.  In Orange County, so many crabs are ending up beaches, where they promptly die, that a stench wafts across the air.  “I’m really hoping they come in and rake them up,” Mary Olsen, a Newport Beach resident, told the Register. “Once they die, they just really smell.”  But not far offshore, the critters are still alive and represent a feast for bluefin tuna.   Red crabs can measure about 5 inches. Photo: Dana Wharf Sportfishing  Anglers are venturing out to hook and spear tuna, while photographers are diving in to take advantage of a rare opportunity to photograph these mysterious crustaceans beneath the surface.  To be sure, the images that appear with this post, all used with permission, help shine the light on Pleuroncodes Planipes, a.k.a. red crab and tuna crab.   The red crab invasion began last month in San Diego. Photo: ©Jim Grant  It’s actually a type of squat lobster, and one of the most abundant species of micronekton (actively swimming organisms, larger than plankton), residing in the California Current.  They can measure about 5 inches and represent a food source for not only tuna, but marlin, sharks, yellowtail, and even some whales. Their typical range is from Chile in South America, to Baja California.  They’re not heavily fished commercially, but some of the larger specimens are marketed as langostino. Those that are dying on SoCal beaches, though, seem to be fit only for starving gulls.  –Note: Underwater photos are courtesy of Geoff Glenn Photography. Click on these links to follow him on Facebook and Instagram  More from GrindTV  Violinist Vanessa-Mae’s Olympic skiing ban overturned  Make ours a double: The ‘Surfer’s Martini’  This week in Vimeo On Demand  #crabs PrevNext  Trending  Baby elephant takes issue with its trunk  This pink elephant is not a hallucination  Births of baby bald eagles captured by webcam  Massive great white shark off Australia said to be ‘the size of Jaws’  Meet the shark with the cleanest set of chompers around  Rare video shows antler falling off a bull moose  'Biggest great white shark ever filmed' surfaces in new video  Menacing shark terrorizes beachgoers in Florida   FEATURED VIDEOS   The Weekly Grind: A crazy sled race and the Rip Curl Pro Bells Beach  BASE jumper leaps off London’s tallest building  Kayaker takes on huge Graceland slide like nobody’s business  Follow mountain biker Mike Hopkins on his fever dream DON'T MISS   U.S. Coast Guard gets kudos for saving baby seal  Behind Thrill  Meet the shark with the cleanest set of chompers around SPONSORED CONTENT BY TRAVEL ALBERTA Thrill in Alberta.  Jon Rose just made it so easy to help people on your next trip for World Water Day  Baby elephant takes issue with its trunk  Tips for traveling with long-distance friends  FOLLOW US   GrindTV.com on Facebook GrindTV.com on Twitter GrindTV.com on Google Plus GrindTV.com on Instagram GrindTV.com on Pinterest GrindTV.com RSS Feed NEWSLETTER  Subscribe ABOUTCONTACTMEDIA KITCAREERSPRIVACY POLICYTERMS OF USEADCHOICES Copyright © 2016 The Enthusiast Network. All rights reserved. Visit our other sites  Yahoo! News Network This website is owned and operated by GrindTV.com. GrindTV.com collects the information you provide on this website. To learn more, please read our Privacy Policy.   Share with friends Facebook Twitter Email Pin It GMail StumbleUpon Reddit Tumblr Google+ Pocket Powered by Po.stPrivacy</p>]]></description>
            <link>undefinedgrindtv-surf-nature-travel-sections-southern-californi/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">57a1a6de-9261-4d06-a567-173ca0f3635d</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 15:37:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>